<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="rfc2629.xslt" ?>
  <!-- generated by https://github.com/cabo/kramdown-rfc2629 version 1.0.36 -->

<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" [
]>

<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc sortrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>

<rfc ipr="trust200902" docName="draft-serf-latest" category="std">

  <front>
    <title abbrev="SERF">Secruity Event Refinement Framework</title>

    <author initials="R." surname="Moskowitz" fullname="Robert Moskowitz">
      <organization abbrev="Huawei">Huawei</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street></street>
          <city>Oak Park</city>
          <region>MI</region>
          <code>48237</code>
          <country>USA</country>
        </postal>
        <email>rgm@htt-consult.com</email>
      </address>
    </author>
    <author initials="H." surname="Birkholz" fullname="Henk Birkholz">
      <organization abbrev="Fraunhofer SIT">Fraunhofer SIT</organization>
      <address>
        <postal>
          <street>Rheinstrasse 75</street>
          <city>Darmstadt</city>
          <code>64295</code>
          <country>Germany</country>
        </postal>
        <email>henk.birkholz@sit.fraunhofer.de</email>
      </address>
    </author>

    <date year="2017" month="February" day="07"/>

    <area>Security</area>
    <workgroup>TBD</workgroup>
    <keyword>Internet-Draft</keyword>

    <abstract>


<t>Security automation requires input of high refinement and high confidence to base corresponding security decisions on. Vital tasks that depend on these refined security events include, integrity of network separation (network slicing), traffic analysis, vulnerability assessment, configuration drift, or malfunction that results in degraded availability or integrity of data. Creating security events of high refinement from the overwhelming amount of (security) events of low refinement is the objective of the solution proposed in this document. This document defines and illustrate five core elements that are required to facilitate a refinement process conducts aggregation, correlation and analysis of event streams with machine learning and AI procedures in a distributed mash of virtual (and sometimes hardware-bound) functions:</t>

<t><list style="symbols">
  <t>an information sharing architecture that is feasible in the thing-2-thing scope, including a pub/sub approach virtual functions that are bundled in SERF components can exchange information with</t>
  <t>an information model that defines the basic set of information elements that provides the features for machine learning functions and AI procedures to produce output of higher refinement that supports
goals in security automation</t>
  <t>a concise data format for events that can be interpreted and processed by every SERF component that consumes (subscribed to) corresponding types of information (topics)</t>
  <t>alternative architecture implementation based on CoAP and CoMI CoAP pub/sub interaction models and SSLS peer-2-peer topics that are brokered via a corresponding resource directory</t>
  <t>integration of content authorization in existing and to be developed building-blocks that compose a SERF domain leveraging solutions developed in the ACE work group</t>
</list></t>

<t>The resulting architecture provides the capability to bundle machine-learning and AI procedures in SERF components that compose virtual functions. SERF components can be migrated and spawned to support dynamically changes in the requirements of processing capabilities to scale with the amount of security events that can spike in cases of malicious acts, such as DDoS or massive system failures. SERF components are able to attest their integrity using traditional remote attestation and emerging attestation procedures (such as TUDA). Heterogeneous sources of security events, such as proprietary anomaly detection components, netflow statistics, automobile ECU, actuators and sensors in ICS, or constrained-node networks in the thing-2-thing scope.</t>



    </abstract>


  </front>

  <middle>


<section anchor="introduction" title="Introduction">

<t>The Introduction goes here</t>

<section anchor="requirements-notation" title="Requirements notation">

<t>The key words “MUST”, “MUST NOT”, “REQUIRED”, “SHALL”, “SHALL NOT”,
“SHOULD”, “SHOULD NOT”, “RECOMMENDED”, “NOT RECOMMENDED”, “MAY”, and
“OPTIONAL” in this document are to be interpreted as described in RFC
2119, BCP 14 <xref target="RFC2119"/>.</t>

</section>
</section>
<section anchor="section-1" title="Section 1">

<t>The meat goes here.</t>

<t>The second paragraph is here</t>

<t><list style="hanging">
  <t hangText='This is:'>
  a defintion</t>
</list></t>

<figure><artwork><![CDATA[
This
is
a
listing

]]></artwork></figure>

</section>
<section anchor="section-2" title="Section 2">

<t>Some more meat here.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="iana-considerations" title="IANA considerations">

<t>This document will include requests to IANA:</t>

<t><list style="symbols">
  <t>first item</t>
  <t>second item</t>
</list></t>

</section>
<section anchor="security-considerations" title="Security Considerations">

<t>There are always some.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="acknowledgements" title="Acknowledgements">

<t>Maybe.</t>

</section>
<section anchor="change-log" title="Change Log">

<t>No changes yet.</t>

</section>


  </middle>

  <back>

    <references title='Normative References'>





<reference  anchor='RFC2119' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc2119'>
<front>
<title>Key words for use in RFCs to Indicate Requirement Levels</title>
<author initials='S.' surname='Bradner' fullname='S. Bradner'><organization /></author>
<date year='1997' month='March' />
<abstract><t>In many standards track documents several words are used to signify the requirements in the specification.  These words are often capitalized. This document defines these words as they should be interpreted in IETF documents.  This document specifies an Internet Best Current Practices for the Internet Community, and requests discussion and suggestions for improvements.</t></abstract>
</front>
<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='14'/>
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2119'/>
<seriesInfo name='DOI' value='10.17487/RFC2119'/>
</reference>




    </references>




  </back>
</rfc>

